Guide to the John N. Paden papers, 1938-2010
George Mason University. Libraries. Special Collections & Archives
- Series 3: Publications, 1959-2010; (37.5 boxes)
  - Guardian, January 24, 1999-November 18, 2005 (Box 112)
  - Guardian, January 12, 2007-February 21, 2010 (Box 113)
  - Leadership, December 20, 2006-April 22, 2007 (Box 113)
  - Leadership, May 18, 2007-February 23, 2010 (Box 114)
  - Mirror, January 6, 2008 (Box 114)
  - Nation, March 3, 2007-December 23, 2009 (Box 114)
  - Nation, January 8, 2010-February 24, 2010 (Box 115)
  - National Concord, July 22, 1980-April 19, 1999 (Box 115)
  - New Nigerian, July 25, 1969-December 12, 1975 (Box 115)
  - New Nigerian, July 8, 1976-July 26, 1980 (Box 116)
  - New Nigerian, July 30, 1980-February 27, 1999 (Box 117)
  - Nigerian Citizen, February 17, 1965-July 7, 1965 (Box 117)
  - Punch, May 26, 1979-January 14, 2008 (Box 117)
  - Nigerian Citizen, bound year, 1959 (Box 118)
  - Nigerian Citizen, bound year, 1960 (Box 119)
  - Nigerian Citizen, bound year, 1964 (Box 120)
    MUST BE TOP BOX.
  - This Day, February 27, 1999-April 19, 2007 (Box 121)
  - This Day, April 20, 2007-January 9, 2008 (Box 122)
  - This Day, January 12, 2008-February 2, 2010 (Box 123)
  - This Day, February 3, 2010-February 22, 2010 (Box 124)
  - Times, January 19, 1976-April 18, 1999 (Box 124)
  - Tribune, April 14, 1979-February 15, 2010 (Box 125)
  - Trust, February 26, 1999-April 23, 2007 (Box 125)
  - Trust, May 10, 2007-February 24, 2010 (Box 126)
  - Vanguard, January 24, 1999-December 27, 2009 (Box 127)
  - Various, 1960s-1970s (Box 127)
  - Various, 1960s-1970s (Box 128)
  - Various, 1970s - 1990s (Box 129)
- Series 4: Maps, 1959-2010; (.5 boxes)
  Includes maps of various African nations, primarily Nigeria. Organized by region and then chronologically.
  - Kaduna State, undated (Box 104, Folder 4)
  - Kano, 1970s (Box 104, Folder 5)
  - Nigeria, 1960s-1970s (Box 104, Folder 6)
  - Samaru Miscellaneous Paper Number 23, 1967 (Box 104, Folder 7)
  - US Government pamphlets on Africa, 1964-1967 (Box 104, Folder 8)
- Series 5: Audio/Visual, 1964-1985; (6 boxes)
  Reel to reel audio tapes, audio cassette tapes, photographs, negatives. Materials are organized by medium, then by subject, and then chronologically.
  - Reel to reel audio tape, A Boori Liturgy from Katsina [A&B], 1967 (Box 105)
    A: 7 ips, "A Boori Liturgy from Katsina" [1967] LADIN ANO and Ensemble Recorded by A. V. King at SOAS, PL 152 Side 1 / B: 7 ips, same, PL 152 Side 2
  - Reel to reel audio tape, A Boori Liturgy from Katsina [C&D] ADD SCOPE NOTE, 1967 (Box 105)
    A: 7 ips, "A Boori Liturgy from Katsina" [1967] LADIN ANO and Ensemble Recorded by A. V. King at SOAS, PL 153 Side 1 / B: 7 ips, same [short], PL 153 Side 2.
  - Reel to reel audio tape, African Curriculum Project. Vol. I. JNP dictation of draft lectures. No tape, March 3, 1969 (Box 105)
  - Reel to reel audio tape, Aminu Kano, no box, undated (Box 105)
  - Reel to reel audio tape, Chief Anthony Enahore Talk 1 of 2, March 28, 1969 (Box 105)
  - Reel to reel audio tape, Chief Anthony Enahore Talk 2 of 2, March 28, 1969 (Box 105)
  - Reel to reel audio tape, marked "Clean", undated (Box 105)
  - Reel to reel audio tape, Kuoupong / Mboya / ? / Kony? / Black U.S.-Africa, undated (Box 105)
  - Reel to reel audio tape, Les 15 ->19 / Lesson 19 ->28. No tape, undated (Box 105)
  - Reel to reel audio tape, Soja/Paden. Discussion of Vol. 1 / DO NOT ERASE, April 7, 1968 (Box 105)
  - Reel to reel audio tape, Unlabeled, no box, undated (Box 105)
  - Reel to reel audio tape, wedding, 1960s (Box 105)
  - Audio cassette, Personal-Marie Paden (Greg and John), undated (Box 106)
  - Audio cassette, Research-A: Sardauna Project.-Documentaries on the life of Sir Ahmadu Bello, Sardauna of Sokoto on TV. B: N.T.A. Kaduna, March 10, 1969 (Box 106)
    Interior of paper insert reads: Garba Gwandu
  - Audio cassette, Research-A: Sardauna Project:-Translation of Chief S. B. Awondy's lecture on Ali Akilu Memorial Lectures. B: Recorded from Radio Nigeria kad on Tuesday, March 10, 1969 (Box 106)
  - Audio cassette, Research-A: (1) Kidan Ganga (chahi)/Brahim Danmani Wakoisin Sardauna. (2) Kidan Kalangun Jatau Kamba Sauar Sardauna. B: Kidan Kukumar ali Dan Saraki Wauar Sardauna- Didan chaji -/Brahim Danmati, undated (Box 106)
  - Audio cassette, Research-A: Kidan Kalangun Alh. Mamman Shata Wauar Sardauma Bahag. & Sardauna Kakarka Dan Fodio 1965, 1973 and 1977 Wasokiau Stausa na Muh. (Sayyed Sardauna). B: Gigaba da Wakar Muh-Sayyed Rubatatun Wauokin Hausa Ma Miali Mai Pampo Zaria _ (Sardauna), undated (Box 106)
    Interior of paper insert reads: Kidan Kalangun Alh-Mamman Shata. 1 Wakar Sardauna (Sardauna Bahag), 2 Sardauna-Kakanka Dan Fodio 1965 Sardauna Ahmadu-April 18, 1973, 3 Sardauna (Sahago-Sardauna Ahmadu Gwauron Giwa 1977, 4 Sardauna Kakanka Dan Fodio 5/73, 5 Rubuttan Wakokin Hausa Na Mohd Sayyed Sokoto Ayyukan Sardauna, 6 Rubutattun Wakokin Hausa Na M. Ali Mai Pampo Zaria (Sardauna)
  - Audio cassette, Research-A: Kidan Kotson Alm-Musa dankwairo Ahmadu Dan Ibrahim, Hiyayye Janzaki, Maza Tsoronka, Mhi Dubun Wasara, Alhamdullihi Daiyaki. B: Yawuce Raini, Simusuhmi (Yazo Haji) etc., undated (Box 106)
    Interior of paper insert reads: Side A Kidan Kotson A-Musa Danwairo, 1 Taiaziyyar Sardauna (Yawuce rani), 2 Ya Buwayi Maza, 3 Ubangi Jiyy Jagaba Sardauna Dan Muhammad, 4 Hiyayye Jan Zaki Mazasukaya Maka Dole Maidamarar Yaki, Al. Amarinai Saishukura
  - Audio cassette, Research-A: Kidan Kotson Alh-Musa Dankwairo Taiaziyyar Sardauna (Yawuce Tangi) Yabuwayi Maza, Ubatangisin Ja Gaba Jhyayye Janzaki. B: Maidamarar Yaki, Ali Amarinah Saishokura, Maidubun Nasara Ahmadu Dan Ibrahim, undated (Box 106)
    Interior of paper insert reads: Kidan Taushin Marigay Awyu Dandano, 1 Wakar alh. Sir Ahmadu Bello Sardauna-Ahmadu Mairaro inda Allah, 2 Kidan Kotson Umaru mai Sa'a wakar Sir Ahmadu Bello, 3 Kidan Solon Haruna Solo Waka Ta'aziyyar Sardauna, 4 High Life-Jiririn Isa Wakar Sardauna, 5 Waken Addinin Musulunci (hausa) na M. Lawal Cediya Buyu Zaria-Musulumtar Da Mutane.
  - Audio cassette, Research-A: Kidan Kukumar Alh-Ibrahim na Jhabu-Wakar Sardauna. B: Cigaba da Waakar Ibrahim Najhabu da Wauar Sardauna Na Ali dan Sapaki, undated (Box 106)
    Interior of paper insert reads: kidan Kukuma na Alhaji Ibrahim na habu, 1 Maisaje dan Maisaje, 2 Kidan Kukumar ali dan Sarari wakar Sardauna
  - Audio cassette, Research-A: Kidan Tandun Garba Shinkafi Wakar Sardauna Kidan Kotson dan Kyana Usakokin Sardauna. B: Cigaba da Wakokin Sardauna Wakar Nigeria, Wakar Gwamnatin Jihar Arewa, undated (Box 106)
    Interior of paper insert reads: Muhtari Isa 31 Ammanu Rd, Funtua
  - Audio cassette, Research-A: (1) Kidan Taushin Aliyu dan Dawo Wakar Sardauna (2) Kidan Kitson Umaru Mah Sa'a Wakar Sardauna. B: Cigaba da Kidan Kotson Umaru Matsa? (3) Kidan Solon Haruna Solo-Wakar Sardauna (3) Highlife-Jibrin Isa-Sardauna (4) Wauen Asdinin Musulunci ?. Lawa ?ya Sardauna, undated (Box 106)
    Interior of paper insert reads: Kidan Kotson Musa Dankuwa, 1 Ahmadu dan Ibrahim Hiyawe Janzaki Maza Sukaya Maka Dole, [no 2] Maza Tsorenka, 4 Alkalin Sokoto, 5 Mai Dubun Nasara, 6 Alhamdu Likkahi dai Yakai, 7 Mai damarar Yaki, side 2. Yawuce Raini simusulmi (Yaazo Haji) Ahmadu dan Ibrahim Baka Yada, Gudun Arnaba
  - Audio cassette, Research-A: Kidan Taushin Mamman s/Taushin Katsina Wakokin Sardauna. B: Wakokin Sardauna na S/Taushin Katsina, undated (Box 106)
    Interior of paper insert reads: Kidan Taushin S/Taushin Katsina wako? Sardauna, 1 Sardauna Ula? Maza, 2 Ahmadu Kambu Gabas ova s/Fade, 3 Yumkura dan Altahim, 4 Jikam Shehu Bello Ahmadi etc.
  - Audio cassette, Research-A: (1) Kijan Taushin Mamman S/Taushin Katsina-Wakar Sardauna (2) Kidan kalangun Illon kalgo (3) Gowar Bakura:. B: Gonar Sardauna: Kidan Sudan na Hamza Kalaf Wakar Sardauna, undated (Box 106)
    Interior of paper insert reads: Kidan Taushin s/taushin Katsina, 1 Wakar Sardauna, 2 Kudan Kalangun Illonkano Gonar Bakura, 3 Kidan Sudan na Hamza kalaf Wakar Sardauna
  - Audio cassette, Research-A: Kidan Taushin Salihu Jankidi (1) Sassalar Sardauna-Ahmadu Kara Shirin (2) Sardauna Jiran Abubakar. B: (1)Sardauna Girmanka Yayi Babba-(2) Sardauna Ya Fashe Fushina I shi (3) Ad da Duniya Gaba dai (4) Aikin Sardauna e-t-c, undated (Box 106)
    kidan Taushin Salihu Jankiki, 1 Sassalar Sardauna-Ahmadu Kara Shirin D? and Gaskiya ?, 2 Sardauna Jikan Abubakar, 3 Sardauna Girmanka Yayi Babba Rika, 4 Sardauna Yafashe Fushinai shi Adda Duniya Gabadai, 5 Aikin Sardauna etc,
  - Audio cassette, Research-A: Sardauna Project: Documentaries on the Life of the late Premier of the North on TV. B: Sardauna Project: Date:, undated (Box 106)
  - Audio cassette, Research-A: Sardauna Project:-Shekara Sa'ad-Now living in Jos (plateau state). B:, undated (Box 106)
  - Audio cassette, Research-A: Sardauna Project:- Usufu Kantu/Sa = O.D.U. A.B.U. Zaria. B:, undated (Box 106)
  - Photographs, Abdulakan, Ahmadu, May 1996 (Box 107, Folder 1)
  - Photographs, Ado Sanmi-, undated (Box 107, Folder 2)
    Photograph is marked on verso "bought Kano Dec 1968." This photograph appears to be older than the others in this collection. It was curled when received. Some conservation work was done.
  - Photographs, book images, 1960s-1970s (Box 107, Folder 3)
  - Photographs, book images, 1960s-1970s (Box 107, Folder 4)
  - Photographs, book images, 1960s-1970s (Box 107, Folder 5)
  - Photographs, book images, 1960s-1970s (Box 107, Folder 6)
  - Photographs, Hayatu, Saidu. Kano, June 1965 (Box 107, Folder 7)
  - Photographs, Newspaper articles, images, 1960s (Box 107, Folder 8)
  - Photographs, Niasse, Ibrahim and others, 1960s (Box 107, Folder 9)
  - Photographs, passport, May 30, 1979 (Box 107, Folder 10)
  - Photographs, marked "People", 1960s (Box 107, Folder 11)
  - Photographs, marked "People", October 13, 1970 (Box 107, Folder 12)
  - Photographs, personal, 1950s-1960s (Box 107, Folder 13)
  - Photographs, personal, 1959-1962 (Box 108, Folder 1)
  - Photographs, marked "People" Research, August 8, 1970 (Box 108, Folder 2)
    All are from same envelope. Date noted is date of development as marked on prints.
  - Photographs, marked "People" Research, Nigeria, June-July 1965 (Box 108, Folder 3)
    General, 1 of 2.
  - Photographs, marked "People" Research, Nigeria, June-July 1965 (Box 108, Folder 4)
    General, 2 of 2.
  - Photographs, marked "People" Research, Nigeria, general, June 1965-May 1970 (Box 108, Folder 5)
  - Negatives, 1960s (Box 108, Folder 6)
  - Slides, Nigeria, Ann Paden, July 1964-November 1965 (Box 109)
  - 31 film canisters and about a dozen rolls of negatives, 1960s-1970s (Box 133)
    British Lit 1-4; Arabic Manuscripts; Arabic #2 Bello ?; Arabic #3 Abdullahi Diya Al-Umma; AK Col (Hausa); AK education (1); AK cont'd military 1907 ?;Kano 1926-39 ?; 1931 conference; NN Colonial Reports #1-4; Diet-Ann; Nig Cit 1956; Abdullahi Imamship; Arabic documents; John Niger/Sokoto, John-Sheikhs, Kano Ol Mosue, Audu & Pidgeon, Kura, garden ? NEPU headquarters; Arabic documents copying for John Paden; seven unidentified. Agfa box marked "for Mrs. Paden" containing negatives; two loose rolls.
    All rolled items are very tightly wound and fragile.
- Series 6: Oversize, 1949-1997; (2 boxes, 3 drawers in map case)
  Maps, posters, a small amount of printed matter, one large photograph, and one large charcoal sketch. Includes maps up to wall size of Nigeria, other nations, and world regions. Materials range from the 1950s-2000s. Materials are organized by medium, then by subject, and then chronologically.
  - Sauna Jac, undated (Box 110, Folder 1)
    Reprinted from The Nigerian Citizen with the story added in Hausa
  - International Seminar on the Economic Status of Muslim Minorities, bound material, December 28, 1981-January 1, 1982 (Box 110, Folder 2)
  - Photograph, group portrait, undated (Box 130, Folder 1)
  - Maps, Kano, undated (Box 130, Folder 2)
  - Maps, master copies on transparency, undated (Box 130, Folder 3)
  - Posters, religious and cultural, undated (Box 130, Folder 4)
  - Maps, negative images, undated (Box 130, Folder 5)
  - Maps, Kano City Districts, 1970 (Box 130, Folder 6)
    Map elements are now in separate pieces. All fragments were originally attached with unknown adhesive to a paper support which was edged with red tape.
  - Maps, Kano, master copies on transparency, undated (Box 130, Folder 7)
    These items are very fragile.
  - Maps, Nigeria, 1960s, 1997 (Box 130, Folder 8)
  - Maps, regional, Africa, other, 1950s-1960s (Box 130, Folder 9)
  - Posters, political, 1960s-1970s (Box 130, Folder 10)
  - Posters, popular culture, 1970s-1980s (Box 130, Folder 11)
  - Posters, religious and cultural, 1960s-1980s (Box 130, Folder 12)
  - Scroll, Chinese, signed, July 7, 1990 (Box MC, Folder 1)
  - Maps, Abuja, undated (Box MC, Folder 2)
  - Maps, Kano, 1950s-1960s (Box MC, Folder 3)
  - Maps, Kano, fabric, undated (Box MC, Folder 4)
  - Maps, Kano City, master copies on transparency, undated (Box MC, Folder 5)
  - Maps, Kano, numbered, 39, 47-49, 56, 1959-1963 (Box MC, Folder 6)
  - Maps, Kano, numbered, 57 (3 copies), 58, 1959-1963 (Box MC, Folder 7)
  - Maps, Kano, numbered, 65-67, 1959-1963 (Box MC, Folder 8)
  - Maps, navigation, 1964-1969 (Box MC, Folder 9)
  - Maps, Nigeria, 1960s-1980s (Box MC, Folder 10)
  - Maps, Nigeria, provinces, 1949-1960s (Box MC, Folder 11)
  - Maps, regional, Africa, world, other, 1950-1990s (Box MC, Folder 12)
  - Maps, wall, Kano State, 1979 (Box MC, Folder 13)
  - Maps, wall, Nigeria, 1978 (Box MC, Folder 14)
  - Maps, wall, Nigeria, 1978 (Box MC, Folder 15)
  - Posters, museum exhibitions, US, 1980s (Box MC, Folder 16)
  - Posters, political, 1984-1985 (Box MC, Folder 17)
  - Posters, political and cultural, 1960s-1970s (Box MC, Folder 18)
  - Posters, popular culture, undated (Box MC, Folder 19)
  - Charcoal sketch, March 13, 1964 (Box MC, Folder 20)
    Newspapers which were folded in with the drawing provided the estimated date.
- Series 7: Realia, undated; (2 boxes)
  Includes a percussion instrument called a "yomkwo," or Nigerian raft zither. Also included are eight Qur'an (Koran) boards. Six have Arabic writing on them. One is undecorated. All realia are undated.
  - "Yomkwo," Nigerian raft zither, undated (Box 131)
  - Box of 7 Qur'an/Koran boards., undated (Box 132)
    All are musty and smell of mildew.